PRE. The way he competed. The way he lived his life.
Without Limits is a drama, romance film directed by Robert Towne.
The life of renowned runner Steve Prefontaine and his
relationship with legendary coach Bill Bowerman.
Steve Prefontaine, played by Billy Crudup.
Bill Bowerman, played by Donald Sutherland.
Mary Marckx, played by Monica Potter.
Frank Shorter, played by Jeremy Sisto.
Roscoe Devine, played by Matthew Lillard.
Bill Dellinger, played by Dean Norris.
Without Limits is a 1998 American biographical sports film.
It is  written and directed by Robert Towne and follows the relationship between record-breaking
distance runner Steve Prefontaine and his coach Bill Bowerman, who later co-founded Nike, Inc.
Billy Crudup plays Prefontaine and Donald Sutherland plays Bowerman.
It also stars Monica Potter, Jeremy Sisto, Judith Ivey,
Matthew Lillard and William Mapother.
The film was produced by Tom Cruise (Cruise and Mapother are cousins) and
Paula Wagner, and released and distributed by Warner Bros.
Due to a very low-key promotional campaign, the $25 million film grossed only $777,000 at the
box office, even though it received positive reviews from many major critics.
Sutherland received a Golden Globe nomination for Best
Supporting Actor for his performance in the film.
The tone is emotional.